when they ripened, should be reserved for pigs alone.
Chapter 4.
By the late summer, the news of what had happened on Animal Farm had spread
across half the county.
Every day, Snowball and Napoleon sent out flights of pigeons, whose
instructions were to mingle with the animals on neighboring farms, tell them
the story of the rebellion, and teach them the tune of Beasts of England.
Most of this time, Mr. Jones had spent sitting in the tap room of the Red Lion
at Willingdon, complaining to anyone who would listen of the monstrous injustice
he had suffered in being turned out of his property by a pack of good-for-nothing animals.
The other farmers sympathized in principle, but they did not at first give him much help.
At heart, each of them was secretly wondering whether he could not somehow
turn Jones's misfortune to his own advantage.
It was lucky that the owners of the two farms which adjoined Animal Farm were on
permanently bad terms.
One of them, which was named Foxwood, was a large, neglected, old-fashioned
farm, much overgrown by woodland, with all its pastures worn out, and its
hedges in a disgraceful condition.
Its owner, Mr. Pilkington, was an easy-going gentleman farmer who spent
most of his time in fishing or hunting, according to the season.
The other farm, which was called Pinchfield, was smaller and better kept.
Its owner was a Mr. Frederick, a tough, shrewd man, perpetually involved in
lawsuits, and with a name for driving hard bargains.
These two disliked each other so much that it was difficult for them to come
to any agreement, even in defense of their own interests.
Nevertheless, they were both thoroughly frightened by the rebellion on Animal
Farm, and very anxious to prevent their own animals from learning too much about it.
At first, they pretended to laugh, to scorn the idea of animals managing a farm for themselves.
The whole thing would be over in a fortnight, they said.
They put it about that the animals on the Manor Farm, they insisted on calling
it the Manor Farm, they would not tolerate the name Animal Farm, were perpetually fighting among
themselves, and were also rapidly starving to death.
When time passed, and the animals had evidently not starved to death,
Frederick and Pilkington changed their tune, and began to talk of the terrible
wickedness that now flourished on Animal Farm.
It was given out that the animals there practiced cannibalism, tortured one
another with red-hot horseshoes, and had their females in common.
This was what came of rebelling against the laws of nature, Frederick and Pilkington said.
However, these stories were never fully believed.
Rumors of a wonderful farm where the human beings had been turned out, and
the animals managed their own affairs, continued to circulate in vague and distorted forms.
And throughout that year, a wave of rebelliousness ran through the countryside.
Bulls, which had always been tractable, suddenly turned savage. Sheep broke down
hedges and devoured the clover.
Cows kicked the pail over. Hunters refused their fences and shot their
riders onto the other side.
Above all, the tune and even the words of Beasts of England were known everywhere.
It had spread with astonishing speed.
The human beings could not contain their rage when they heard this song, though
they pretended to think it merely ridiculous.
They could not understand, they said, how even animals could bring themselves
to sing such contemptible rubbish.
Any animal caught singing it was given a flogging on the spot.
And yet, the song was irrepressible.
The blackbirds whistled it in the hedges, the pigeons cooed it in the elms.
It got into the din of the smithies and the tune of the church bells.
And when the human beings listened to it, they secretly trembled, hearing in
it a prophecy of their future doom.
Early in October, when the corn was cut and stacked and some of it was already
threshed, a flight of pigeons came whirling through the air and alighted in
the yard of Animal Farm in the wildest excitement.
Jones and all his men, with half a dozen others from Foxwood and Pinchfield, had
entered the five-barred gate and were coming up the cart track that led to the farm.
They were all carrying sticks, except Jones, who was marching ahead with a gun in his hands.
Obviously, they were going to attempt the recapture of the farm.
This had long been expected, and all preparations had been made.
Snowball, who had studied an old book of Julius Caesar's campaigns, which he had
found in the farmhouse, was in charge of the defensive operations.
He gave his orders quickly, and in a